They did the one thing the Nazis never expected. They fought back.
Uprising is a drama, history, war film directed by Jon Avnet.
In the Warsaw ghetto in 1943, Jews rise against the Nazis.
Tosia Altmann, played by Leelee Sobieski.
Mordechaj Anielewicz, played by Hank Azaria.
Icchak 'Antek' Cukierman, played by David Schwimmer.
SS-Brigadeführer Jürgen Stroop, played by Jon Voight.
Adam Czerniaków, played by Donald Sutherland.
Kazik Rotem, played by Stephen Moyer.
Uprising is an American 2001 war drama television film about
the Warsaw Ghetto Uprising during the Holocaust.
The film was directed by Jon Avnet and written by Avnet and Paul Brickman.
It was first aired on the NBC television network over
two consecutive nights in November 2001.
The film explores themes of rebellion, jewish ghetto,
world war ii, deportation, uprising.
The tone is emotional.